{
    "id": "956a7c0b67f044dfa8fb43f3217c12da",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "My friend ………………………….. for about a month.",
            "description": "Use the present perfect to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "is ill",
                "has been ill",
                "has ill"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "71dd340791b9444f8be0e1b8d4daf506"
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he …………………………………. her last year.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to talk about the earlier of the two past actions.",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "had seen",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e39126b856e94de3a374c371a3aee8c8"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………………… my work before he came to see me.",
            "description": "The past perfect is not exactly necessary to indicate that an action had finished before another action commenced. We can express the same idea using the conjunctions before and after.",
            "answers": [
                "finished",
                "had finished",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "98941eb8ef144a93ac1844ee53a3c0a2"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………….. before his mother arrived.",
            "description": "The past perfect is not exactly necessary to indicate that an action had finished before another action commenced. We can express the same idea using the conjunctions before and after.",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "had left",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "389a516387fa4fafab7c14ebada21da7"
        },
        {
            "question": "The show ……………………………. before we reached the venue.",
            "description": "The past perfect is not exactly necessary to indicate that an action had finished before another action commenced. We can express the same idea using the conjunctions before and after.",
            "answers": [
                "began",
                "had begun",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2a6efa5ba0a14984a0502b2d3924e92d"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………………. his wealth shortly after he ………………………………. it.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used for the earlier of the two actions the simple past is used for the later action. ",
            "answers": [
                "squandered away, had inherited",
                "had squandered away, inherited",
                "had squandered away, had inherited"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4aed985cc6de4e2e8a4e4b33e2c1f911"
        },
        {
            "question": "When I reached there I found that the tiger ……………………………….",
            "description": "We use the past perfect for the earlier of the two actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "disappeared",
                "had disappeared",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b1ba746e7442418b9905a53f00693599"
        },
        {
            "question": "He lost his temper before I ……………………………… a word.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "said",
                "had said",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2956ac97078148b0b352605611d628fd"
        },
        {
            "question": "My friend …………………………….. in Mumbai since",
            "description": "To talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present, we use present perfect or present perfect continuous tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "is working",
                "has been working",
                "was working"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ce8ed4f0a2984de79aa320ce1cefe1c3"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………………. for you since 8 o’clock.",
            "description": "To talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present, we use present perfect or present perfect continuous tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "is working",
                "has been working",
                "was working"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0830526aaf9743a39f26ef3414c858cc"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………………. to school by bus.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about habits, routines etc.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "am going"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "12fa4b95f99241aca666c988515d0bbb"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………….. him to go.",
            "description": "We say tell before a personal object.",
            "answers": [
                "said",
                "told"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ec3e0c2434d24c298c5aaa9bdabb0b01"
        }
    ]
}